(Music)
(موسيقى)
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Thank you.
شكرا لكم
Imagining a solo cello concert,
تخيل حفل تشيللو منفرد,
one would most likely think of Johann Sebastian Bach
في الغالب سيفكر الشخص في جوهانز سباستيان باخ
unaccompanied cello suites.
اجنحة التشيللو غير المصحوبة
As a child
كطفلة
studying these eternal masterpieces,
دراسة هذه الروائع الخالدة
Bach's music would intermingle
موسيقى باخ سوف تتمازج
with the singing voices of Muslim prayers
مع الاصوات الغنائية لصلاة المسلمين
from the neighboring Arab village
من قرية العرب المجاورة
of the northern Kibbutz in Israel
لشمال كيبوتز في اسرائيل
where I grew up.
حيث ترعرعت
Late at night, after hours of practicing,
في وقت متأخر من الليل ,بعد ساعات من التدريب
I would listen to Janis Joplin and Billie Holiday
كنت استمع الى جانيس جوبلين و بيلي هوليداي
as the sounds of tango music
و اصوات موسيقى التانغو
would be creeping from my parents' stereo.
تزحف من ستيريو والداي
It all became music to me.
كلها اصبحت موسيقى بالنسبة لي
I didn't hear the boundaries.
لم اسمع الحدود
I still start every day
مازلت ابدأ كل يوم
practicing playing Bach.
بممارسة عزف باخ
His music never ceases
موسيقاه لا تتوقف ابدا
to sound fresh and surprising to me.
ان اسمعها كانها جديدة و مدهشة بالنسبة لي
But as I was moving away
لكني كنت اذهب بعيدا
from the traditional classical repertoire
من الذخيرة التقليدية الكلاسيكية
and trying to find new ways
و محاولة ايجاد طرق جديدة
of musical expression,
للتعبير الموسيقي
I realized that with today's technological resources,
ادركت ان موارد تكنولوجيا اليوم
there's no reason to limit
ليس هناك سبب لحد
what can be produced at one time
ما يمكن انتاجه في مرة واحدة
from a single string instrument.
من اداة موسيقية واحدة
The power and coherency
القوة و التماسك
that comes from one person hearing, perceiving and playing all the voices
التي تاتي من سمع شخص واحد ,ادراك وعزف جميع الاصوات
makes a very different experience.
تصنع تجربة مختلفة كثيرا
The excitement of a great orchestra performance
اثارة اداء اوركسترا رائع
comes from the attempt to have a collective of musicians
يأتي من محاولة اخذ جماعة من الموسيقيين
producing one unified whole concept.
لانتاج مفهوم واحد موحد
The excitement from using multi-tracking,
الاثارة من استخدام مسارات متعددة
the way I did in the piece you will hear next,
كما فعلت انا في المعزوفة التي ستسمعوها لاحقا
comes from the attempt
تأتي من محاولة
to build and create a whole universe
لبناء و خلق كون كامل
with many diverse layers,
مع طبقات متعددة و مختلفة
all generated from a single source.
كلها مولدة من مصدر واحد
My cello and my voice are layered
صوتي و التشيللو خاصتي على طبقات
to create this large sonic canvas.
لخلق هذا القماش الصوتي الكبير
When composers write music for me,
عندما يكتب الملحنون موسيقى لي
I ask them to forget what they know about the cello.
اسألهم ان ينسو ما يعرفونه عن التشيللو
I hope to arrive at new territories
اتمنى ان اصل الى مناطق جديدة
to discover sounds I have never heard before.
لاكتشف اصوات لم اسمعها من قبل
I want to create endless possibilities
اريد خلق امكانيات لا نهائية
with this cello.
بهذا التشيللو
I become the medium through which the music is being channeled,
اصبح الوسط الذي تتوجه عبره الموسيقى
and in the process, when all is right,
و في خلال العملية ,عندما يكون كل شيئ صحيح
the music is transformed
الموسيقى تتحول
and so am I.
و انا كذلك
(Music)
(موسيقى)
(Applause)
(تصفيق)